[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b454", "question": "Where did Abraham Lincoln give his historic speech?", "answer": "Gettysburg, Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd661f6a5bfecdd737e0840", "question": "What country has hosted the most Olympics?", "answer": "USA", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f9", "question": "Which MLB player lead the American league in home runs in 2010 and 2011", "answer": "Jose Bautista", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a4", "question": "Kathy Bates won the best actress Oscar in 1990 for what movie?", "answer": "Misery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad82", "question": "Who became the monarch after Henry VIII?", "answer": "Edward VI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c3", "question": "How many labours did Hercules perform to free himself from bondage?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5b", "question": "Which fairytale character slept for 20 years?", "answer": "Rip Van Winkle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee1", "question": "What bird was used as an alias for Tom Clancy's CIA agent in the Kremlin?", "answer": "The Cardinal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71a", "question": "What is Santa's name in Spain?", "answer": "Papa Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda1", "question": "What are the \"ten\" referred to when a surfer \"hangs ten\" on a wave?", "answer": "His ten toes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd174ec223966ae8f88bf", "question": "In \"Finding Nemo\", where is the dentist's diploma from?", "answer": "Pixar University", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f265cee580c7f8fd1e52", "question": "Who said, \"Winners never quit, and quitters never win.\"?", "answer": "Vince Lombardi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94c", "question": "Pnigerophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Smothering", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e8", "question": "James Bay forms the southern end of what larger bay?", "answer": "Hudson Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600b87f21d8c1817608d53ec", "question": "What was the name of British Prince Philip's mother?", "answer": "Princess Alice of Battenberg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592ead5df83302ff91e4647b", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b958", "question": "Who was pictured on the first US adhesive stamp?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a808", "question": "What country has the largest number of citizens living within the Arctic Circle?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a547", "question": "What is the capital of Oregon?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fa", "question": "The sleeve insignia of a First Class Petty Officer in the US Navy is a spread eagle over how many chevrons?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a63842ebb971c1417fb9a", "question": "Which band released the song \"Proud Mary\" in 1969?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396da", "question": "What kind of wine does Hannibal Lecter recommend while enjoying a human liver?", "answer": "Chianti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0de1dfcbed638185eaa12", "question": "Which city has the biggest helicopter fleet in the world?", "answer": "Sao Paulo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a7c220565ad31a57c7ee", "question": "Where was paper first produced?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77cee124f0f7a362efd549", "question": "Where is the Rosenstiel School of Marine and Atmospheric Science Located?", "answer": "Virginia Key, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e95f77ccba3ffe45786e6", "question": "Whose autobiography was entitled \"The Sport of Queens\"?", "answer": "Dick Francis'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a177", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Kimono My House\"?", "answer": "Sparks\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabb", "question": "Which part of the body suffers from Microphthalmia?", "answer": "The eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b42d", "question": "What year did Alfred Hitchcock become a citizen of the United States?", "answer": "1955", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea375bff048f679a45ab17", "question": "What is the second derivative of displacement?", "answer": "Instantaneous Acceleration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a2", "question": "What nation is named for the Hapsburg king of Spain from 1556 to 1598?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600e0e381d348e9c6eed4815", "question": "How many people (military and civilians) in the Soviet Union died from World War II.", "answer": "Approximately 27 million people died as a result of the war, which represented 15% of the population of the country.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad81", "question": "Which French king built the Palace of Versailles?", "answer": "Louis XIV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6670252a821ff76ae8afb", "question": "May Day was banned in England during which century?", "answer": "For a few years in the mid 17th Century, the church abolished May Day due to its revelrous nature.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be77", "question": "What does an NFL referee signal by stretching his arms out at his sides with his palms down?", "answer": "Unsportsmanlike Conduct", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c17", "question": "What year was the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\" first aired in?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173cac44491cbd7c5a17a7", "question": "How did Saturday get its name?", "answer": "Saturday is named for Saturn. The word is derived from S\u00e6turnesd\u00e6g\u00a0in Old English,\u00a0dies Saturni\u00a0in Latin and samedi\u00a0in French.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0c", "question": "What homerun hitter was nicknamed the \"Sultan of Swat\"?", "answer": "Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e61", "question": "What word for a wimp comes from the title character of Harold Webster's comic strip \"The Timid Soul\"?", "answer": "Milquetoast", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f95b02755722f97b22684db", "question": "What does Dumbledore give to Ron in his will?", "answer": "Deluminator", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ddc306d333868d34d708", "question": "In which developed nation was unemployment the highest in the 1920's?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7bc", "question": "Of the 88 keys on a piano, how many are black?", "answer": "36", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8afb901dd7bf43be5e78a", "question": "What is the term for a word that is spelled the same forwards and backwards?", "answer": "Palindrome", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339402", "question": "Which actor played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 movie \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0d", "question": "What is the fear of fog known as?", "answer": "Homichlophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff66f3f52a821ff76ae8b1d", "question": "What popular prank object is outlawed in Mobile, Alabama?", "answer": "Silly string", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a7f5ed6f5f79087132fb41", "question": "Which 1980s wrestling superstar once played baseball in the St. Louis Cardinals' minor league system?", "answer": "\"Macho Man\" Randy Savage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b7", "question": "From which movie did the phrase \"You can't handle the truth!\" originate?", "answer": "A Few Good Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c2", "question": "What is Albumen the correct term for?", "answer": "Egg White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3c", "question": "During what decade did the Charleston become the dance craze?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61a", "question": "Which company introduced Comet cleanser back in 1956?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c270", "question": "What is February's birthstone?", "answer": "Amethyst", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c2", "question": "Who does Bruce Banner turn into when he gets angry?", "answer": "The Hulk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d07e91a1c922dd1ac64bd", "question": "Which Science Fiction author wrote \"The Day of the Triffids\"?", "answer": "John Wyndham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e89", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Griffin?", "answer": "Eagle and lion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd968de23c87fd04dd15e05", "question": "What did the BBC broadcast on the \"day without news\" in 1930?", "answer": "Piano music", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b299", "question": "Who was the only slave ever known to have stayed in Thomas Jefferson's household?", "answer": "Sally Hemings", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a969", "question": "What California peak, which erupted in 1915, is the world's largest lava dome?", "answer": "Lassen Peak", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1e", "question": "Which rabbit was the hero of some of Beatrix Potters stories?", "answer": "Peter Rabbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e4", "question": "What is Chicago's main international airport?", "answer": "O'Hare", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ed", "question": "What was Daniel's last name in 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "LaRusso", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d81", "question": "Whose paintings include \"The Red Room\", \"The Green Stripe\", \"The Blue Nudes\" and \"The Yellow Odalisque\"?", "answer": "Henri Matisse's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c056", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Israel?", "answer": "Hoopoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b69", "question": "What was the first sports-themed movie to win the Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Rocky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c515", "question": "What disease is the focus of oncology?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe523411bf59ab7d2e380ee", "question": "Where was Winona Ryder caught shoplifting?", "answer": "Saks Fifth Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec86bcec223966ae8f8811", "question": "Who was the first female artist in history to have 4 consecutive singles from one album reach the Top 5 in the Billboard Hot 100?", "answer": "Cyndi Lauper's 1983 classic \"She's So Unusual\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f81001dd7bf43be5e83e", "question": "Pteromerhanophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Flying", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af3", "question": "What was Dr. Seuss' real name?", "answer": "Theodor Seuss Geisel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a2", "question": "In which city could you find Bondi beach?", "answer": "Sydney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f6", "question": "What 1970's TV show spawned the catchphrase \"Up your nose with a rubber hose\"?", "answer": "Welcome Back, Kotter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339443", "question": "Which Bond actor won an Academy Award for his role in \"The Untouchables\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b78de662d71a53651013", "question": "Alan Frew, author of 2007's \"The Action Sandwich\", was also lead singer for which 80's pop group?", "answer": "Glass Tiger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a257", "question": "How old was Alfred Hitchcock when he died?", "answer": "80", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a10d", "question": "In the \"Nightmare On Elm Street\" films, who played the role of Freddy Krueger?", "answer": "Robert Englund", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ab", "question": "Tornadoes are columns of air that generally come into contact with what kind of clouds?", "answer": "Cumulonimbus cloud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca29", "question": "Where on the human body is the ulnar loop?", "answer": "Finger", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e97", "question": "What movie did the villain Noah Cross appear in?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b0", "question": "What Canadian singer was married to Mutt Lange?", "answer": "Shania Twain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339327", "question": "In the 1975 movie \"Jaws\", what was the name of Quint's boat?", "answer": "The Orca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e0", "question": "Which famous actress was born Vera Jane Palmer?", "answer": "Jayne Mansfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada2", "question": "Robert Leroy Parker was better known as who?", "answer": "Butch Cassidy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4b", "question": "What movie was Robert Downey Jr.'s first movie?", "answer": "Pound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2bd", "question": "What rival faction split from the Bolsheviks at the Communist Party Congress of 1903?", "answer": "The Mensheviks", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14c", "question": "How is Samuel Langhorne Clemens better known?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea8386ff048f679a45ac28", "question": "What is the minimum speed for a Category 5 hurricane?", "answer": "157 mph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e4a", "question": "What's the name of the little boy who discovers \"Where the Wild Things Are\"?", "answer": "Max", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbaf", "question": "In karate, what color belt is earned just before black?", "answer": "Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37f", "question": "A male duck is properly known as what?", "answer": "A drake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd6", "question": "According to legend, what outlaw killed one man for each of the 21 years he lived?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3cc544f0f6af5b066634", "question": "What year did Bill Haley and His Comets release the album \"Rock Around the Clock\"?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dbe2e748bb36357acdd9", "question": "What is the smallest marine mammal?", "answer": "The Sea otter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339482", "question": "Who directed the 1969 movie \"The Wild Bunch\"?", "answer": "Sam Peckinpah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1bf", "question": "What US president was a personal friend of Sam Houston?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaad87e83c707845b20e2", "question": "Who created the centigrade scale, which was later renamed in his honor?", "answer": "Anders Celsius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339308", "question": "In the 1987 movie \"Fatal Attraction\", what animal did the obsessed woman cook on the stove?", "answer": "A rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a523", "question": "What is the capital of Lithuania?", "answer": "Vilnius", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ccf7851b37b32637bdc44b9", "question": "Who has won the most NFL MVP awards (as of 2019)?", "answer": "Peyton Manning (5)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5cc", "question": "What is the name given to the largest number ever used in a mathematical proof?", "answer": "Graham's Number", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecd988ec223966ae8f88e3", "question": "Who was the initial casting choice for the role of the Terminator?", "answer": "O.J. Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a660", "question": "What modern-day US state was inhabited by the Pequot Indians?", "answer": "Connecticut", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d47071f8e329de4f877891", "question": "What year was cricketer Phil Tufnell born?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8ac8e01dd7bf43be5e76d", "question": "Succulent is derived from the Latin word \"sucus\", meaning what?", "answer": "Sap", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff3", "question": "What movie star founded the Hole in the Wall summer camps for ill children?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a619", "question": "The Makah Indians lived on which coast?", "answer": "West coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b4", "question": "Gouda cheese originated in which country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f534fa5fdd6dd25324ec", "question": "Daniel Keyes wrote which 1959 Hugo-award winning science-fiction novel?", "answer": "Flowers for Algernon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d118bc4fea7fe947a22287", "question": "How many successive Wimbledon titles did Bjorn Borg win?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6a", "question": "What egyptian object is also known as \"The Key to the Nile\"?", "answer": "Ankh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc3096ce05a3942286f1c", "question": "In the film \"The Usual Suspects,\" Roger \"Verbal\" Kint supposedly suffers from what ailment?", "answer": "Cerebral palsy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a4e220565ad31a57c7c3", "question": "What amusement park was home to America\u2019s first roller coaster?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff1", "question": "Fred Astaire's character in \"Funny Face\" was based on what fashion photographer?", "answer": "Richard Avedon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339739", "question": "Which artist was born Artis Leon Ivey Jr.?", "answer": "Coolio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97d", "question": "What nuts are used to make a Satay sauce?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca17", "question": "What is used to measure horizontal and vertical angles in surveying?", "answer": "A theodolite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339795", "question": "What was Mohammed Ali said to float like?", "answer": "A butterfly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002431a4be4723ccac22190", "question": "How is the author Eric Arthur Blair better know?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971dd8e89261e916c8e099e", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1990\u2019s TV show \"Grace Under Fire\"?", "answer": "Brett Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91b", "question": "What does the abbreviation \"AT&T\" stand for?", "answer": "American Telephone and Telegraph Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c95", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Capeside, Massachusetts?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f167c0f7c52aae91cc07bd", "question": "The Republic of Guinea-Bissau has a coast on which ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ad", "question": "What was the Asian nation of Myanmar known as prior to 1989?", "answer": "Burma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59decff3ea2747c8aff16d22", "question": "Illyngophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Veritgo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f4", "question": "How many claws does a housecat have?", "answer": "Eighteen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdffb071cf6db9ac4808cf3", "question": "What U.S. state is home to \"The Raisin Capital of the World\"?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923a", "question": "What superhero sidekick is known as Boy Wonder?", "answer": "Robin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b6", "question": "Which English city was actor Stephen Fry born in?", "answer": "London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc83eec223966ae8f8890", "question": "After Andy gets assaulted and beaten, who exacts revenge on the one who perpetrated it in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Captain Bryon Hadley cripples Bogs, the leader of the group that assaults Andy.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b640eee65b76b9f2667", "question": "Which seven U.S. states seceded and formed the original Confederacy during the U.S. Civil War?", "answer": "Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, South Carolina and Texas.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3e0044f0f6af5b066643", "question": "Andorra is bordered by which two countries?", "answer": "France and Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3cf9e4f032c0db195b491", "question": "In which caste would you most likely find a Hindu priest?", "answer": "Traditionally, priests have come from the Brahmin varna.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f1", "question": "What US state has been governed by Philip La Follette and Tommy Thompson?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2b", "question": "What year was the novel \"A Brave New World\" written?", "answer": "1931", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca35", "question": "What instrument is used for measuring the distance between two points on opposite sides of an object?", "answer": "Caliper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8f", "question": "What kind of animal is pictured on the wrapper of a Klondike bar?", "answer": "Polar bear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6a", "question": "Who is the only American-born member of Monty Python?", "answer": "Terry Gilliam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20f6e31a458464a93c434", "question": "Who wrote the 1952 novel \"Invisible Man\"?", "answer": "Ralph Ellison", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "593c4becb8198b9a2b077967", "question": "In which of the \"Die Hard\" films does Samuel L. Jackson star in?", "answer": "Die Hard with a Vengence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a9", "question": "What US city is nicknamed \"The Big Peach\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b888", "question": "Which continents have never hosted the Olympics?", "answer": "Antarctica and Africa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba1", "question": "What famous movie actor got his start playing the first openly gay nationally broadcast TV character, in the late 1970's?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f8", "question": "How many natural satellites does Jupiter have?", "answer": "79", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b3", "question": "Which movie was the first feature film made entirely in CGI?", "answer": "Toy Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0de59fcbed638185eaa15", "question": "Which U.S. state has the longest width east to west?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cf", "question": "What area of the Atlantic is said to be responsible for the disappearance of ships and aircraft?", "answer": "Bermuda Triangle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a3c8300039f3d7859290ff6", "question": "In the TV Show \"Bonanza\", what was \"Hoss\" Cartwright\u2019s given name?", "answer": "Eric", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339553", "question": "Who played Mork and Mindy's baby?", "answer": "Jonathan Winters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14d", "question": "Which female singer collaborated with Eminem for the song \"Stan\"?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e72c999d0874f1a5e2d1c1e", "question": "What famous suffragette was born Araminta Ross?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfbbd9dc5ec6cd98a8317", "question": "What painting is featured prominently in the 2007 film \"St Trinian's\"?", "answer": "Johannes Vermeer's\u00a0\"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d1158c4fea7fe947a22267", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc0fed469bb8041d07a069", "question": "Which beer is from the \"land of sky blue waters\"?", "answer": "Hamm's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5aab2eb858d116dab4aecb41", "question": "Who played the role of Wayne Szalinski in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Rick Moranis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ef", "question": "Of the six main cast members on the TV show \u201cFriends\u201d, which was the oldest?", "answer": "Lisa Kudrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f4", "question": "Which song did Doris Day sing in three different films?", "answer": "Que Sera Sera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7692ceec85e375820b2ad", "question": "What is the Welsh name for Wales?", "answer": "Cymru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5963724f967692ea851899be", "question": "A jellyfish is made up of 95% of what?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ba", "question": "Which is the world's northernmost capital city?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea47c3ff048f679a45abad", "question": "What strangely named type of mackerel is also known as an Ono in Hawaii?", "answer": "Wahoo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f2b", "question": "Which band member of The Blues Brothers died of drug overdose?", "answer": "John Belushi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f9", "question": "What does IQ stand for?", "answer": "Intelligence Quotient", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd69fa76c0f9723ab15cb2d", "question": "What was Martin Luther King, Jr.'s birth name?", "answer": "Michael", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba5", "question": "Who was the first American team to join the National Hockey League, in 1924?", "answer": "Boston Bruins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde4a62c6c6b019850c9a74", "question": "What was the warship that exploded in Havana Harbor, precipitating the Spanish-American War?", "answer": "USS Maine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bce8fb6c85e9e634ff62", "question": "Dakar is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e4", "question": "What 4 seas are named for colors?", "answer": "Red, White, Yellow and Black", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe25a30658e585fda9cfa44", "question": "What does the term \"au gratin\" mean when it comes to cooking?", "answer": "Covered with browned crust, often breadcrumbs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a210", "question": "Jason Voorhees' mask was molded from which NHL team's goalie mask?", "answer": "Detroit Red Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46d", "question": "Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay were the first people to do what?", "answer": "Reach Mount Everest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afaa", "question": "St. Albans was the start and Bosworth field was the finish of what?", "answer": "War of the Roses", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd9", "question": "Lansing is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a40620565ad31a57c7b9", "question": "What is the oldest of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World?", "answer": "Great Pyramid of Giza", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acec", "question": "What Canadian city boasts the world's richest rodeo that was first staged in 1912?", "answer": "Calgary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a609", "question": "In which European country is the resort town of Spa?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b233", "question": "St. Louis' Gateway Arch is officially named for what US president?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c2084f032c0db195b47d", "question": "Who was the first wife of King Henry VIII?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389da", "question": "What war saw the bombing of Guernica that inspired one of Picasso's most moving paintings?", "answer": "Spanish Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febac047e83c707845b20ea", "question": "What was the name of the last known Pinta Island tortoise?", "answer": "Lonesome George", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c8", "question": "How many pounds of jet fuel does a passenger Boeing 747 use during take off?", "answer": "Almost 6,000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acef", "question": "What was U.S. President Wilson's first name?", "answer": "Thomas (Woodrow was his middle name)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c516", "question": "How many stars are in the Big Dipper constellation?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b494", "question": "Which country hosted the 1900 Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56c", "question": "Phobos is the name of one of the moons of which planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3efeb8b5801b8f54a7fb8", "question": "Which software giant was founded in Albuquerque, New Mexico in 1975?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a4", "question": "What screenplay won George Bernard Shaw a 1938 Oscar?", "answer": "Pygmalion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b85f", "question": "Which car company produced a model named the Celica?", "answer": "Toyota", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d2", "question": "How many land miles are there in a league?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339193", "question": "Who is the villain in Disney's \"101 Dalmatians\" animated adaptation?", "answer": "Cruella de Vil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9704323c87fd04dd15e47", "question": "Which US state was the first to officially recognize Christmas?", "answer": "Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339691", "question": "What movie contains the line \"I'm going to make him an offer he can't refuse\"?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16810f7c52aae91cc07c1", "question": "Which opera singer was known as \"La Stupenda\"?", "answer": "Joan Sutherland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b891364247bf200fb882", "question": "The Easter lily is a plant endemic to which Japanese islands?", "answer": "Ryukyu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecdb69ec223966ae8f88f5", "question": "The script for what movie was written during shooting breaks on the set of \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "E.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049990cf93664eb1048693", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f6b4ff048f679a45aadd", "question": "What did Albert Einstein win the Nobel Prize for in 1921?", "answer": "For his discovery of the law of the photoelectric effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5be76ce05a3942286e1a", "question": "Flora, Fauna, and Merryweather are fairies in which Disney classic?", "answer": "\"Sleeping Beauty\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af1", "question": "In which US state was Clark Kent brought up?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbb", "question": "What was the first US city to have a public school system?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c946", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for krypton?", "answer": "Kr", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339532", "question": "What show featured the five orphaned Salinger siblings?", "answer": "Party of Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20f", "question": "Which country hosted the first Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ef", "question": "In a 2003 movie, Diane Lane plays a writer who buys a villa in what region of Italy?", "answer": "Tuscany", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb1137e83c707845b210b", "question": "Which planet was discovered by mathematical prediction before it was directly observed?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbee06ce05a3942286ef8", "question": "Who recorded the song \"King for a Day\"?", "answer": "Thompson Twins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a08", "question": "What snack shares its name with the famous cartoon strip by Charles M. Schulz?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c04", "question": "What novel portrays the life of the Joad family during the Great Depression?", "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3eac538e4e5d4832e6315", "question": "On which day of Creation did God make the land and seas?", "answer": "Third", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339518", "question": "What movie earned John Wayne his first Academy Award?", "answer": "True Grit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abcf", "question": "What country is home to the Bank of Alexandria?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8bc", "question": "What is the more common name for Tympanum?", "answer": "Eardrum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a4", "question": "Who played the role of Peter Bretter in the 2008 movie \"Forgetting Sarah Marshall\"?", "answer": "Jason Segel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37a010ada16518afdc057", "question": "What mascot represented the women who went to work in factories to help with the war effort during World War II?", "answer": "Rosie the Riveter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa71", "question": "Rioja wine comes from which country?", "answer": "Spain\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339220", "question": "Who were the principal members of the band \"The Beatles\"?", "answer": "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c368", "question": "What acid gives citrus fruits their distinctive sharp flavor?", "answer": "Citric acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e21", "question": "What movie is loosely based on Philip K. Dick's novel \"Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep\"?", "answer": "Blade Runner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a1cc20565ad31a57c7a7", "question": "The authors of the Federalist Papers used which pseudonym?", "answer": "Publius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5bde6ce05a3942286e19", "question": "The Jeffersons\" was a spinoff of what show?", "answer": "\"All in the Family\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c541", "question": "Icthyologists study what?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6000edf09a72b906b34e3cf2", "question": "What is the name of the largest vein in the human body?", "answer": "The inferior vena cava", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d9", "question": "What island nation was ruled by \"Papa Doc\" and \"Baby Doc\" Duvalier?", "answer": "Haiti", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e8", "question": "In the movie \"The Terminator\", what did the cyborg remove in order to repair itself?", "answer": "Its eyeball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fff", "question": "What British TV series featured Saffron and Bubble?", "answer": "Absolutely Fabulous", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dac", "question": "What novel's long-promised sequel is called \"Buttercup's Baby\"?", "answer": "The Princess Bride", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf9", "question": "What country is the Mekong Delta located in?", "answer": "Vietnam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a50c", "question": "The Hagia Sophia is located in what country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7abacb6490a8cc1a6e5291", "question": "What is the gravitational field strength on the moon?", "answer": "1.6N/kg", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6e", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Fred Jones?", "answer": "The Mystery Machine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc6", "question": "What kind of flower does saffron come from?", "answer": "A crocus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc1abec223966ae8f886c", "question": "Makeup artist Joanna Balkin says she needed 40 bottles of sunscreen per month to protect what 1990s TV show\u2019s cast from sunburns?", "answer": "\"Baywatch\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac1c", "question": "What is the capital of Suriname?", "answer": "Paramaribo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b2", "question": "What is the top color on the neck of the guitar in the Guitar Hero game?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72c", "question": "What \"h\"\u00adword is the unit of measurement used to determine the height of a horse?", "answer": "Hand", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bd05d3e40191c55fd523fb6", "question": "Who is the archenemy of Spider-Man?", "answer": "Spider-Man doesn't have a single archenemy but a number of them", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba49", "question": "During what decade was the first Super Bowl played?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5be57fa55415ba52ed6f0aad", "question": "In which European city would you find the Rijksmuseum?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e8a8a26404ad935a7e1a642", "question": "In what country was Shakira born?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d6", "question": "What is the only US state with a single syllable name?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c037", "question": "What race takes place on an annual basis between Putney and Mortlake?\u00a0", "answer": "Oxford and Cambridge Boat Race\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b37506d333868d34d6d7", "question": "Who discovered the island of Tierra del Fuego?", "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339985", "question": "In the TV show \"Friends\", who played the role of Rachael's sister, Jill?", "answer": "Reese Witherspoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51c89ff04d658268c9317", "question": "Who served as the Minister of Armaments and War Production in Nazi Germany during most of World War II.", "answer": "Albert Speer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f4", "question": "What day is the Super Bowl always played on?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc42", "question": "What country was tennis player Novak Djokovic born in?", "answer": "Yugoslavia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef8", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Isabel Archer?", "answer": "The Portrait of a Lady", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e9", "question": "What group's 1979 debut album was entitled \"Reproduction\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df2", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"commando\"?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cddb5e347d002c297e4f3", "question": "Which 1960s singer/songwriter was voted \"Ugliest Man on Campus\" while attending college?", "answer": "Janis Joplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600241484be4723ccac22174", "question": "What famous author tried to get his wife committed to an insane asylum so he could live with his 18-year-old mistress?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8a", "question": "How long did Pope John Paul I serve?", "answer": "33 days", "category": "history"}]